(Sincro: wyxchari)
Retain full pressure.
保持最大压力
Full pressures being maintained on master control.
主控已经保持在最大压力上.
Reserves are standing by.
备用系统待命中
Let me see. Let me see.
让我看看, 让我看看
Doctor, what could be happening to Jamie now?
博士, Jamie 现在会怎样?
I hate to think.
It won't be anything very pleasant.
我不敢去想. 不会是什么愉快的事情
Polly, go and see what the first dial
on the control desk registers.
Polly, 过去看看控制台上第一个读数
Right.
好
Hurry up.
快点
Full pressure.
满压
Full pressure. And the other one?
满压. 另外一个呢?
Come on.
快点
Zero.
零
Zero. Now I think there's only one thing for it.
零. 现在我觉得只有一种可能
Plus must be made minus and minus must be made plus.
加得变成减, 减得变成加
What's the matter?
什么情况?
The question is which is plus
and which is minus?
问题是哪个是加, 哪个是减?
Ooh.
噢
What are you doing?
你在做什么?
Oh, just checking.
哦, 只是检查一下
Well, I don't need your help, thank you.
好吧, 我不需要你的帮助, 谢谢你
As you please. But, uh, I think
you're going to run into trouble.
你高兴就好. 不过, 啊, 我觉得你要陷入麻烦了
Why? What's the matter?
为什么? 什么情况?
Well, according to my calculations,
the pressure gauges are wrong.
哦, 根据我的计算, 压力表读数是错的
Don't be ridiculous.
别瞎说了
Ridiculous? Well, that's as may be.
瞎说? 好, 也有这个可能.
But, after all, three times three is nine,
但是, 毕竟, 3 乘 3 得 9
and if you divide by half of
its own cubic capacity to the formula,
然后如果你按这个公式用它容积的一半去除
Pi over four squared,
I think you'll have to agree with me.
４π的平方, 我想你就不得不认同我了
Don't touch that.
别碰那个
Why not?
为什么不能?
That's the... That controls the inflow system.
那是...那东西控制着流入系统
Oh. So these are the inflow pipes, are they?
哦. 那么那些就是流入的管道, 是吧?
That's all I wanted to know.
我就想知道这个
But what are you doing?
不过你要做什么?
Inflow. Inflow. Outflow. Inflow.
流入, 流入, 流出, 流入,
High pressure. Low pressure and O-U-T spells out.
高压, 低压, 然后是 O-U-T
Doctor, what are you doing?
博士, 你在做什么?
It's alright, Polly.
Confusion is best left to the experts.
没事的, Polly. 混乱最好留给专家来处理
But... Stop it!
You've no idea what you're doing.
但是...停下! 你不知道你在做什么
Oh, yes I have.
哦, 我知道.
I can stand an operation on its head
quicker than anyone. There!
我可以从头进行操作比谁都快. 那里!
I think you'll find I've revolutionised
the entire gas flow of the Colony.
我想你会发现我已经革新了这个殖民地的整个瓦斯流向
You must be mad. You'll be locked up.
你肯定疯了, 你会被关起来的
Polly, see what those dials register now.
Polly, 现在去看看那些仪表读数
Right. Doctor?
Something's happened to this one.
好的. 博士? 这一个出了点问题
What does it read?
它什么读数?
It's reads zero.
读数为零
And the other one?
另外一个呢?
- Full pressure.
- Good. Splendid.
- 满压  - 好, 非常好
That means there'll be
a fine old gale of fresh air...
这意味着将有一大股冷空气
blowing along the old shaft any time now.
很快将沿着旧竖井吹过去
Ah! Ah! Let go! No! Let...
啊! 啊! 放开! 不! 放...
Not yet, you're not.
还不到时候, 你不能
You can do nothing.
You'll only delay matters.
你什么也做不了, 只会延误事情
It's a simple matter for me to reconnect the gas.
我要重新连通瓦斯是很简单的事情
Yes, I'm sure it is.
But I'm sure you'd like a little help.
是的, 我确信是这样. 但我也确信你需要一点点帮助
Now stop that.
You've enough to answer for already.
现在别再瞎说了. 你已经有足够多的问题要回答了
Guard! Guard!
警卫! 警卫!
It's all right, Polly.
I've got his keys. Lock the door.
没事的, Polly. 我拿了他的钥匙. 锁上门
Send the guard, immediately!
派警卫过来, 立刻!
They're bound to get in sooner or later.
他们迟早肯定会来的
Yes. Well, the later the better.
是, 不过, 越迟越好
The only thing we can do for Jamie
now is to give him time.
现在我们唯一能为 Jamie 做的, 就是给他时间.
Lock the door.
锁上门
This is Control.
Why has the outflow of gas stopped?
这里是管理员. 为什么流出的瓦斯停下来了?
Gas must be pumped into the old shaft
without interruption.
瓦斯必须泵入到旧竖井里面, 不得间断
Begin pumping immediately.
立即开始泵入
I need help immediately.
The strangers obey nothing.
我急需帮助. 异乡人什么都不遵守
They are turning taps in the wrong direction.
他们把阀门都转到了错误的方向
Guards have been detailed to assist you.
已经向警卫详述了情况, 他们过来帮你
Open up in there!
里面把门打开!
Keys! My keys! Where are my keys?
钥匙! 我的钥匙! 我的钥匙在哪儿?
Oh, dear. Your keys. Try, uh, in your pocket.
噢, 亲爱的, 你的钥匙. 啊, 试试你的口袋
Or on the gantry. Or over there.
或者在台子上, 或者在那边
Look, I know you've got them.
听着, 我知道你拿走了
Doctor, the door.
博士, 门
Open up in there or we'll smash it in.
里面把门打开, 否则我们就砸了
It's going to give way.
快要扛不住了
Come on, Polly. Let's get out of here.
快点, Polly, 我们离开这里
No, not that way - it goes to the pits.
不, 不能走那边 - 那通向矿坑
- Quick. Try that one.
- It's locked.
- 快点, 试试那个  - 被锁住了
Then use the keys. Quick, Doctor. Quick!
那就用钥匙啊. 快, 博士, 快!
Over there. Quick!
Stop them before they do any damage.
在那边, 快! 快阻止他们, 以免他们搞破坏
Get them!
抓住他们!
Push, Polly! Push!
推, Polly! 推!
- I can't!  - You've got to.
- 我不行!   - 你必须得
Come on. Together.
I've nearly got it locked.
加油, 一起. 我快把它锁上了
There we are.
这下好了
- Where are we?  - Well...
- 我们在哪儿?   - 这个..
It looks rather like a cupboard
with a lot of pipes.
看起来是一个碗柜, 上面多了好多管道
Where do you suppose they lead?
你觉得它们通向哪里?
They must lead somewhere. Let's have a look.
它们肯定通向某个地方. 我们去看看
Doctor, I think these are the pipes
that carry the poisonous gas.
博士, 我觉得这些管道里面跑的是那些有毒瓦斯
Yes, very likely.
是的, 很有可能
Well, don't you think we'd better stay here?
那, 你不觉得我们最好待在这里吗?
Stay here? I'm not spending the rest
of my life with a lot of old pipes.
待在这里? 我可以不打算跟一大堆破管子共度余生
- But Doctor...
- Now, come along Polly.
- 但是博士...  - 现在, 过来吧, Polly
I'm sure there's no need to be afraid.
我确信没有必要害怕
Well... well, I think there's no need
to be afraid.
这个...我觉得没有必要害怕
Oh, come on. Let's find out.
噢, 快点, 我们去搞明白
There, that ought to do it.
Let's hope we're not too late.
那里, 那应该可以了. 期望我们没有太迟
What do you know?
你们知道些什么?
We all know Control is right,
and we must obey!
我们都知道管理员是对的, 而且我们必须服从
Let them know. Let them know.
让他们知道, 让他们知道
Let them know they're happy!
让他们知道他们很幸福!
Greet the morning with a shout.
向着清晨喊一声你好
Everyone up. The sun is out.
所有人都起来, 太阳出来了
- Rah, rah, rah!﻿
Cheer for the Colony.
We're the gang that works the hardest,
为殖民地欢呼. 我们是工作最努力的团队
and we must obey.
Obey Control. Ring the bell.
我们必须服从. 服从管理员, 获得赞许
- Rah, rah, rah!﻿
- Work well.  - Ring the bell!
- 好好工作  - 获得赞许!
Oh, that's much better.
噢, 这次好多了.
But, we'll do it again,
and this time with more feeling.
但, 我们要再来一次, 这次多带点感情
Ah! And don't forget our job is
to inspire the others
啊! 而且不要忘了我们的任务是要鼓舞其他人 -
- our brave workers who are doing
such a dangerous job.
那些干着如此危险工作的勇敢工人
- All right?
- All right!
- 好吗?   - 好!
What do you know?
你们知道些什么
We all know Control is right,
and we must obey!
我们都知道管理员是对的, 而且我们必须服从
Let them know. Let them know.
让他们知道, 让他们知道
Let them know they're happy!
让他们知道他们很幸福!
Greet the morning with a shout.
向着清晨喊一声你好
Everyone up. The sun is out.
所有人都起来, 太阳出来了
- Rah, rah, rah!﻿
Oh, that's very good!
That's beginning to sound like something.
噢, 这次非常好, 听着开始像点样子了
It still needs a bit more clarity,
and I think that the girls could...
还需要更清晰一点点, 而且我觉得姑娘们可以...
Say! how did you get there?
说说! 你怎么到那里的?
Oh, w... well, uh... I just,
um... as a matter of fact...
噢, 我...这个, 啊...我只是, 唔...事实上
Oh, I see. You're one of the dancers.
哦, 我明白了. 你是跳舞队的
One of the dancers? Oh, I'm afraid, uh...
跳舞队的? 哦, 恐怕, 啊...
Aye. Aye, y... yes. I'm one of the dancers.
是, 是, 是的, 我是其中一员
And you got your dance ready?
那你准备好你的舞蹈了吗?
My dance? Ah... Well, uh...
我的舞蹈? 啊...这, 啊...
Yes. Yes, it's ready.
是的, 是的, 准备好了
Well, go ahead. I'll see it now.
那, 开始吧. 我现在要看看
You'll see it now?
你现在就要看?
And don't forget you have to be very good
而且不要忘了, 你必须表现非常好
to get into the Happy Colony finals.
才能进入快乐殖民地的决赛
We want something gay and cheerful.
我们想要欢乐明快的
Gay and cheerful?
欢乐明快的?
Have you any music?
你有音乐吗?
Ah, no. I don't need it.
啊, 不, 我不需要
Go ahead. We'll pick up the rhythm
and clap to it.
开始吧. 我们会跟着节奏打拍子
- All right?
- All right!
- 好吗?   - 好!
Well, come on. Get on with it.
We haven't got all day.
好, 快点. 开始跳啊, 我们没有一整天
Oh, aye.
噢, 是
That's very good.
这相当不错啊
- What do you call it?
- The Highland Fling.
- 你管它叫什么舞?   - 高地猛冲
Why do you call it the Highland Fling?
你为什么管它叫高地猛冲?
Because we finish the dance
by flinging ourselves out the door.
因为这个舞蹈的结尾动作都是冲出门去
Oh, that's very good! Come on now.
哦, 这太棒了! 现在都来
- Rah, rah, rah!﻿
Cheers for the Colony. Rah, rah, rah!
为殖民地欢呼, Rah, rah, rah!
Where did this boy come from?
这个男孩儿哪里来的?
- Oh, he's one of the dancers.
- Nonsense. He's the escaped stranger.
- 哦, 他是跳舞队的  - 胡说. 他是那个逃跑的异乡人
You there - identify him.
Is this the boy you reported?
你 - 指认一下, 这是你报告的那个男孩吗?
Well... Well... Yes.
唔...唔...是的
Ben, you gave me away.
Ben, 你出卖我
Tie him up. Go to the Pilot.
把他绑起来. 到领航员那里去,
Tell him the stranger's found.
告诉他异乡人已经找到了
Tell him it won't be long before we
get our hands on his friends as well.
告诉他不用太久我们也会抓到他的朋友们了
Jamie, I'm...
Jamie, 我...
No permission is granted for the guards
警卫没有获得授权
to go on forbidden ground.
不能进入禁地
- Repeat, no permission.
- Shh. I hear voices.
- 重复, 没有权限  - 嘘, 我听见有声音
Very faint.
很弱
(They are not to cover the exit to the old shaft.)
(他们不得去把守旧竖井的出口)
I don't hear anything.
我什么也没听见
(This is in use at this moment by Control.)
(当前它正在被管理员使用)
- Stay here a minute, Polly.
- No. Don't leave me.
- 在这里待一小会儿, Polly  - 不, 别扔下我
(No one is to go near the old shaft.)
(任何人不可进入或者靠近旧竖井)
The search for the other strangers
must be carried on.
对其他异乡人的搜索工作必须继续
It's the Controller.
The voice behind the screen.
是管理员. 屏幕后面的那个声音
All guards are detailed to hunt
for the Doctor and the girl.
所有警卫都仔细搜寻博士和那个女孩儿
They must be taken dead or alive.
无论死活, 必须找到
Look! He must be there.
看! 他肯定在那里
This is Control.
这里是管理员
The day shift is to begin work
in the emergency gas shaft.
白班即将开始在紧急瓦斯竖井中工作
All pressures are to be maintained.
The Colony cannot live without gas!
必须保持瓦斯压力. 没有瓦斯殖民地无法存活!
So that's where all the gas goes.
看来所有瓦斯都去了那里
Yes. Just as I thought.
是的, 如我说料.
These creatures would die without it.
没有它们这些生物就会死
But how long have they been there?
但它们在那里多久了?
I mean, they weren't always in control, were they?
我是说, 不会一直都是它们掌权, 是吧?
I couldn't tell you when they were here
in the first place, Polly.
我无法告诉你它们一开始是什么时候在这里的, Polly
They're like germs in the human body.
它们就像人类身体内的细菌一样
They've got into the body of this colony.
它们进入了这个殖民地的身体
They're living as parasites.
像寄生虫一样生活
You make it sound like a disease.
你说得好像一种疾病似的
Polly, that's what I think they are.
Polly, 我觉得它们就是那样
They're in the control room.
它们在控制室里面
It must be like getting into the brain, mustn't it?
这肯定就像是钻进大脑一样, 是不是
Yes. Very likely.
是, 非常可能
Shh. They might hear you.
嘘, 它们可能会听到你
Now then. One system must provide them
with the gas they need,
现在看来, 一个系统肯定是给它们提供所需的瓦斯的
and the other one must be an outflow.
另一个肯定是排出口
Doctor, we've got to bring the Pilot here.
博士, 我们得带领航员到这里来.
Then we can show him
these creatures really do exist.
然后展示给他看这些生物真的存在
Yes, Polly, I think it might work.
是的, Polly. 我觉得这样可行
Look at me when I talk to you.
我跟你说话的时候, 要看着我
Ola, a word with you.
Where exactly did you catch him?
Ola, 问你一句, 你具体是在哪里抓住他的?
In here. In the hall, Pilot.
在这里, 大厅里, 领航员
I see. So, in fact, he gave himself up?
我明白了. 这么说, 事实上, 他是自首的?
He should never have been allowed to escape.
本来就不应该允许他逃跑
Are you criticising Control?
你是在批评管理员吗?
I'm criticising the running of the pits.
我是在批评矿坑的运作
But that is my job, Ola.
但那是我的工作, Ola
I know that. But were it not for my guards,
我知道那个. 但如果不是我的警卫,
this stranger would still be
a danger to all of us.
这个异乡人仍然是我们所有人的危险
I am going to report to Control that
there is no discipline in the pits.
我要向管理员报告, 矿坑毫无纪律
That's not the only report that
Control will get!
那可不是管理员会收到的唯一报告!
Ever since these strangers arrived
自从这些异乡人的到来,
your authority in this colony has gone to pieces.
你在这个殖民地的权威已经崩溃了
They come and go as they please,
他们想来就来, 想走就走
and even now two of them are still missing.
就是到现在他们还有两个人不知去向
Good morning. Good morning. Good morning.
早上好, 早上好, 早上好.
Well, everyone is up bright and early.
好, 每个人都早早起床了
And the last two strangers
are not missing after all.
最后两个异乡人也没有失踪.
Oh, come now.
哦, 现在来吧
You can't have bad temper
and differences of opinion
你不可能会有坏脾气和不同意见
in this happy type colony.
这是个幸福的殖民地
Say you're sorry, Ola.
Say you're sorry, Pilot.
说你很抱歉, Ola. 说你很抱歉, 领航员
Doctor, what did ye come here for?
博士, 你来这里做什么?
- You've walked into a trap.
- Good morning, Jamie.
- 你走进了陷阱里了  - 早上好, Jamie.
It's nice to see you so well cared for.
很高兴看到你受到如此多的照顾
- Yes, but Doctor...
- Oh, it's all right. It's all right.
- 是, 但是博士...  - 哦, 没事的. 没事的
I've just come in to have a word
with my old friend, the Pilot.
我只是进来跟我们的老朋友, 领航员, 说两句话
Good morning, Ben. I hope
you're feeling more your old self?
早上好, Ben, 我期望你觉得更像是以前的你了
Yes, Doctor. I am.
是的, 博士, 我是
Why did not your guards arrest these strangers?
为什么你的警卫不把这些异乡人逮捕起来?
I don't know. Guards, arrest them!
我不知道. 警卫们, 逮捕他们!
That is no longer necessary.
不在有这个必要了
Of course not. You can't arrest us
now we've given ourselves up.
当然没有. 现在我们都投降了, 你不能逮捕我们
That's against the rules.
这违反规则
Now. You wish to see me?
现在, 你们想要见我?
Yes. I do. Urgently. Come with me.
是的, 我想. 很紧急, 跟我来
This is Control. Everyone is to return
to work immediately.
这里是管理员. 所有人立即返回工作岗位
This order includes all executives.
It includes the Pilot.
这项命令也包含管理层, 包含领航员
Everyone back to work immediately.
所有人返回工作岗位, 立即
- Well, I shall have to go.
- No, wait.
- 那, 我不得不走了  - 不, 等等
You must listen to
what the Doctor's got to tell you.
你必须听听博士要告诉你的事情
They're only saying that because
they know what we've seen.
他们那么说仅仅因为他们知道我们看见了什么
- At once!
- Pilot.
- 马上!   - 领航员
At once! That is an order!
马上! 这是命令!
Don't take any notice of them./29.1
别理会他们
That's not your Controller.
Those are your enemies.
那不是你们的管理员, 那是你们的敌人
There must be no discussion
with the strangers!
不允许同异乡人进行讨论
Why not?
为什么不?
Aye. What are you afraid of?
是, 你在害怕什么?
Arrest the strangers! That is an order!
All the strangers!
逮捕异乡人! 这是命令! 所有异乡人!
That doesn't sound like a man in control.
那听起来不像是一个掌权的人
What did you wish to tell me?
你想要告诉我什么?
Pilot. You heard Control.
领航员, 你听到管理员的话了
Guards, take them all away.
警卫, 把他们带走
I am still the Pilot here.
You will take your orders from me.
我仍然是这里的领航员. 你得听从我的命令
Get back to your quarters.
回到你们的房间去
Contact Control immediately.
Report the Pilot!
立即联系管理员, 举报领航员!
That was a very brave thing to do.
那可真是非常勇敢的行为
Or very foolish.
What is it you wanted to tell me?
或许是非常愚蠢. 你想要告诉我的是什么?
Come with me.
跟我来
- Pilot!
- You will all remain here.
- 领航员!   - 你们全部都留在这里
He disobeyed Control.
The Pilot will be arrested.
他不服从管理员. 领航员得被逮捕
No.
不
Anything may happen now, Jamie.
现在什么都可能发生, Jamie.
We've got to be ready to run for it.
我们得准备好逃跑
We can't leave the Doctor.
我们不能撇下博士
He'll be back in a minute,/15.3
他一会儿就会回来,
and Ben seems to be all right now.
而且 Ben 现在似乎也没事了
More like the old Ben, I must admit.
But you still canna...
更像以前的 Ben 了, 我必须承认. 但是你还是不能...
Where is he?
他在哪儿?
But, Doctor. This is forbidden territory.
但是, 博士, 这里是禁地
Yes, and you'll soon see why.
是的, 而且你很快就能看到为什么
Stop! Stop! You're breaking the law!
停下! 停下! 你是在违反法律!
Bad laws were made to be broken. Follow me.
坏的法律制定出来就是要违反的. 跟我来
But...
但是...
What's happened to the Pilot, Ola?
领航员发生什么事了, Ola?
The strangers have changed him!
那些异乡人已经改变了他!
The Pilot is a traitor.
领航员是个叛徒
The Pilot has no more authority.
Ola is in command!
领航员不再具有权力了. Ola 负责指挥!
I really don't know why I trust you, Doctor.
我真的不知道为什么我相信你, 博士
Oh, perhaps I've got an honest face.
哦, 也许是我有一张诚实的脸
The Pilot is to be arrested!
领航员将被逮捕!
This is a happy colony! All must obey!
这是一个幸福的殖民地! 所有人都要服从!
Did you hear that?
你听到那个了吗?
Don't give up now. It's just up here.
不要现在放弃. 就在上面这里
All guards to report to the pit head.
所有警卫带矿口坑报到
They are to take orders from Ola.
It is understood?
从 Ola 那里接收命令. 明白了没?
There you are.
That's what's taken over this colony.
这就是啦, 那就是接管了这个殖民地的东西
You haven't been in touch
with Control, but with these.
跟你们接触的不是什么管理员, 而是这些
They've used this colony for their own ends,
他们利用这个殖民地达到他们自己的目的,
destroying you to live themselves.
毁灭你们来让他们生存
Why...they're horrible.
为什么...它们太吓人了
No, Doctor. It is they who must be destroyed.
不, 博士. 它们才是必须被消灭的东西
We must kill them.
我们必须杀死它们
- They're here!  - Let's go.
- 他们在这里!   - 我们走
The Pilot and the stranger!
In forbidden territory!
领航员和异乡人! 在禁地里!
They must be destroyed!
他们必须被消灭!
So, what are they, Doctor?
那, 它们是什么, 博士?
I mean, some monstrous form of bacteria?
我说, 某种可怕的细菌吗?
Insects? Or what?
昆虫? 或者别的?
I don't know. But you must fight them.
我不知道, 但你必须同他们斗争
How?
怎样斗?
Take full command!
全面夺权!
You mean defy Control?
你的意思是反抗管理员?
Well, you see what Control really is.
是, 你都看见了管理员真正是什么
Yes. You're right, Doctor,
they must be destroyed.
是, 你是对的, 博士. 必须消灭它们
We've been waiting for you.
我们在等你呢
Ola, the Colony is in the hands of
grotesque insects!
Ola, 殖民地在这些怪诞的虫子手中!
So you've been seeing things?
所以你也能看见东西啰?
They're in there. The Macra!
它们在这里, 那些 Macra!
Ha, ha, ha. You know
what happens to people that say that?
哈哈哈, 你知道说这个的人都怎么样了吗?
But I...
但是我...
Now we can deal with you all together.
现在我们可以一并处理你们了
Did the Pilot has see them?
领航员看见它们了吗?
Yes. I saw the Macra.
是的, 我看见 Macra 了
It is forbidden to say that.
这么说是被禁止的
Don't let him say that he has seen Macra!
别让他说他见过 Macra!
I saw you! You are the Macra!
我见过你! 你就是 Macra!
Silence! Silence the three strangers!
安静! 三个异乡人都闭嘴!
That is an order!
这是命令!
What shall we do with them, Control?
我们要拿他们怎么办?
Return them to the pipe room.
The three strangers and the Pilot.
把他们送到管道室, 三个异乡人和领航员
They are to be locked in,
and you will not let them out.
他们要被锁起来, 你不能让他们出来
Come on, get in.
快点, 进去
- Ola.  - Doctor!
- Ola  - 博士!
Come on. You heard Control. Get in.
快点, 你听到管理员的话了. 进去
Don't worry Polly, I'll look after ye.
别担心 Polly, 我会照顾你的
- No!
- Take your hands off her!
- 不!   - 把你的手拿开, 别碰她!
Get in!
进去!
You have done well, Ola.
你做得很好, Ola
What instructions, Control?
什么指示, 管理员?
Clear the building. Guards and workers
are to return to the hall for music.
清空大楼. 警卫和工人们都返回大厅听音乐
I obey, Control.
我服从, 管理员
It will take precisely four minutes,
将需要正好四分钟
and then it will be safe for everyone
to return to work.
然后每个人就可以安全地回去工作了
- Four minutes.
- Why four minutes?
- 四分钟  - 为什么是四分钟?
Aye, what can they do in four minutes, Doctor?
是, 四分钟里面它们能做什么, 博士?
I don't know. We must be ready for anything.
我不知道, 我们必须准备应对一切
It's a gas! It's coming in here.
是瓦斯! 进这里来了
Pilot, do you know where it's coming from?
领航员, 你知道它是从哪里来的吗?
Why, no. I've never been here before.
为什么, 不. 我以前从没来过这里
There must be a hidden inlet.
肯定有一个隐秘的入口
You will not be able to fight it.
You cannot stop it.
你们没法对抗它, 你们阻止不了它
Doctor, I'm getting dizzy.
博士, 我头晕了
Polly, hold that in front of your mouth.
Polly, 把这个捂在你口鼻上
It's coming from over here, Doctor!
它是从这里来的, 博士!
You're right, Jamie!
你是对的, Jamie!
It's coming from here as well!
它也可以从这里出来了!
You are unable to stop it.
你们没法阻止它的
- Polly?  - It will not last long.
- Polly?  - 不会太长时间
Only for four minutes.
只有四分钟
- By that time, you...
- Come on! Let us out!
- 到那个时候, 你们...  - 快点! 让我们出去!
...will be completely helpless,
not quite dead, helpless.
...将会完全无力, 还没有完全死, 而是无力
Hello in there.
里面的人呐
- Who is it?  - Ben.
- 是谁?  - Ben
Ben? Is that you? Are you all right?
Ben? 是你吗? 你没事吧?
Can you open the door from your side?
你能从你那边打开门吗?
No.
不能
But it's locked. There isn't a key.
它是锁上的, 没有钥匙
Ben, listen. We've got very little time.
It's all up to you.
Ben, 听着, 我们只有很少的时间了. 全靠你了
Go ahead Doctor. Tell me what to do.
继续博士, 告诉我该怎么做
Go to the control desk,
and you'll see two switches,
到控制桌去, 你可以看到两个开关
one marked outflow and one marked inflow.
一个标记着流出, 一个标记着流入
Hang on.
坚持住
The other stranger has recovered.
He is now dangerous!
另外那个异乡人已经恢复了. 他现在很危险!
He will no longer obey Control.
他不再服从管理员了
The fourth stranger is trying to help his friends.
第四个异乡人试图帮助他的朋友
He is no longer one of us.
He must be stopped at once!
他不再是我们的一员了. 必须马上阻止他!
I've got them, Doc.
Two switches. What next?
我找到它们了, 博士. 有两个开关, 然后怎样?
Good. You see a lever in front of them?
好, 你看见它们前面有个拉杆吧?
Yeah, right first time.
嘢, 第一时间就看见了
It is forbidden to touch that instrument!
You must not obey the Doctor!
触碰那个设备是禁止的! 你不能听从博士的!
You will kill us all!
He intends to create an explosion!
你会杀死我们全部的! 他打算引发一场爆炸!
Come away from those instruments!
You will destroy the Colony!
离开那些仪器! 你会毁了殖民地的
Oh, shut up. Okay, Doctor. Fire away.
噢, 闭嘴! 好了, 博士, 点火啦
Guards! Stop the stranger!
警卫! 阻止那个异乡人!
Switch on both inflow and outflow.
同时打开流入和流出
No! Stop! The pressure will be unbearable for all!
不! 停下! 压力将会变得没谁能够忍受!
The human beings as well...
人类也会...
Switch them on, Ben.
Then stand by to throw the lever.
把它们打开, Ben. 然后准备推拉杆
You are to give no such order!
你不要给这样的命令!
Inflow on. Outflow on.
流入打开, 流出打开.
Okay, Doc. Ready with the lever.
好了, 博士. 准备操作拉杆了
Quickly, Doctor!
快点, 博士!
Throw the lever away from you.
将拉杆推离你
No! No! Don't let him.
不! 不! 不能允许他
No!
不!
Now, my first duty is to thank the strangers,
现在, 我的第一个职责是要感谢这些异乡人,
for they have saved our Colony.
感谢他们救了我们的殖民地
A dance festival will be held every year
in their memory,
舞蹈节会每年举行, 以纪念他们.
and the winners will be awarded
the Strangers' Trophy.
比赛获胜比赛的人会赢得异乡人奖杯
Where's the Doctor?
博士哪里去了?
He's playing his pipe over there.
他在那边吹他的笛子
Well, I've got a tip-off he'll wanna hear.
哦, 我有一个秘报他肯定想听
Hey, Doctor? Doctor?
嘿, 博士? 博士?
Relax. Relax. More haste, more waste.
放松, 放松. 越着急就越浪费.
Pleasure is beautiful.
快乐是美丽的
Relax? You wait till you hear
what they're going to do with you.
放松? 你等着听听他们要把你怎么样
Oh, well? Ha, ha, ha.
噢, 怎样? 哈哈哈
Yeah, I just heard it on the grapevine.
是的, 我刚才在葡萄架fixme上面已经听到了
They're going to draft us as members of the Colony,
他们要把我们列为殖民地的成员,
and make you the next Pilot.
让你担任下一任领航员
They can't do that to me.
他们不能这么对我
- Let's get out of here.
- Yes, but how?
- 我们离开这里吧  - 好, 但怎么能走?
Take a leaf out of Jamie's book.
Give them the old dance routine.
从 Jamie 的书里扯一页, fixme